homemademedicine.com 2012-10-10

# Homemade Medicine Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Personal Information  
The HMM may collect personally identifiable information such as name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address, institution affiliation, credit card number, checking account number, or date of birth through various activities of the Society. This personal information is collected and used by HMM staff for the purpose of facilitating a relationship or business transaction. 

The HMM website resides behind a firewall and uses SSL (Secure Sockets Layer, the industry-standard security protocol used to communicate with browsers) to transmit personal information. Data is strongly encrypted during transmission to ensure that personal and payment information is secure. Industry-standard data encryption techniques are used to protect personal information on HMM computers. SSL-capable browsers typically have a symbol on the browser window to indicate when they are in a secure mode. In addition, the URL will begin with "https:" for all browsers.

E-mail  
The HMM does not sell or rent e-mail addresses to other organizations. Certain e-mail addresses may be published in both print and electronic HMM publications including the HMM website. The HMM may generate e-mail for the following types of communication:   
Notification e-mail to which the individual may subscribe and unsubscribe.   
Transactional e-mail, which is the result of a business transaction initiated with the HMM.   
Relationship e-mail, which is sent as an informational service because of a relationship with the HMM.   
Commercial e-mail, which is sent to promote an HMM product or service (You may opt not to receive this type of e-mail).   
Correspondence from HMM staff as a result of a communication initiated by a member or customer.   
E-mail that has a provision for opt-out will include instructions on how to do so. All inquiries regarding subscription-based e-mails should be directed to the HMM Member and Customer Services Department (see HMM Contact Information below). 

Mailing Lists  
Postal mailing list’s, comprised of full name and postal address, may be sold to other organizations (e.g. professional societies and/or commercial publishers) for one-time promotional or informational use. Promotional or informational materials are subject to HMM approval prior to the rental. E-mail addresses are not included in mailing lists.

The HMM may occasionally send informational or promotional materials to members and customers. You may choose to exclude yourself from all, none, or only non-HMM mailings by contacting the Member and Customer Services Department (see HMM Contact Information).

Third-party Agents   
The HMM uses third-party agents for several business purposes, including credit card validation, hotel registration, and shipping. These agents are permitted to use your personal information only to provide the HMM with a specific service and not for any other purpose. Please contact the HMM Member and Customer Service Department (see HMM Contact Information) if you believe this policy has been violated.

The HMM makes every effort to preserve your privacy, but we may need to disclose personal information when required by law. The HMM may also disclose personal information if it believes in good faith that such action is necessary.

Non-personal Information   
Non-personal information is collected behind the scenes by the HMM web server and is used to compile general website usage statistics or facilitate access to restricted website services. Such information includes:

IP address of computer   
Browser-related information   
Locations visited on the website   
HTTP cookies   
IP address  
IP address is used to verify access rights of licensed subscribers to HMM products that require license agreements, such as HMM Electronic Journals. They also aid in the general administration of the website.

HTTP Cookies  
A HTTP Cookie is a piece of data that is stored by your browser in either your computer’s memory or on your computer’s hard drive. The HMM uses cookies to keep track of user session identity on the website, such as tracking items in a bookstore shopping cart or maintaining access to restricted website services via the HMM Web Account. Cookies are also used to track the effectiveness of various services provided on the HMM website. Browsers generally allow you to disable cookies. Services on the HMM website that require a login to an HMM web account require that cookies are enabled.

Public Forums  
Several public forums are hosted on the HMM website. The inherent public nature of these forums dictates that the HMM assumes no responsibility for protecting the information disclosed on them by users. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in public forums.

External Links  
The only domain covered by the HMM privacy policy is HMM.com. The HMM website may contain links to other sites, however, and the HMM is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those external sites.
